<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5"><character><version>37</version><uid>1165</uid><name>Bard Level 1</name><abilities>8,14,10,12,13,15,</abilities><hpMax>8</hpMax><hpCurrent>8</hpCurrent><unarmed>1</unarmed><race><name>Aarakocra</name><speed>25</speed><age>15</age><height>15</height><weight>15</weight><eyes>15</eyes><skin>15</skin><hair>15</hair><feat><name>Flight</name><text>You have a flying speed of 50 feet. To use this speed, you can&#39;t be wearing medium or heavy armor.

Source: Elemental Evil Player&#39;s Companion, p. 5</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Talons</name><text>You are proficient with your unarmed strikes, which deal 1d4 slashing damage on a hit.

Source: Elemental Evil Player&#39;s Companion, p. 5</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Language</name><text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Aarakocra, and Auran.

Source: Elemental Evil Player&#39;s Companion, p. 5</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><mod><category>1</category><type>1</type><value>2</value></mod><mod><category>1</category><type>4</type><value>1</value></mod><spellAbility>6</spellAbility></race><background><name>Augen Trust (Spy)</name><align>15</align><faction>15</faction><personality>15</personality><ideals>15</ideals><bonds>15</bonds><flaws>15</flaws><proficiency>104</proficiency><proficiency>116</proficiency><feat><name>Description</name><text>Although your capabilities are not much different from those of a burglar or smuggler, you learned and practiced them in a very different context: as an espionage agent. You might have been an officially sanctioned agent of the crown, or perhaps you sold the secrets you uncovered to the highest bidder.
Source: Explorer&#39;s Guide to Wildemount</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Starting Proficiencies</name><text>Your background grants you the following proficiencies.

Skills: Deception, Stealth

Languages: none

Tools: one type of gaming set, thieves&#39; tools</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Criminal Contact</name><text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 130</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Equipment</name><text>A crowbar, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Personality Trait</name><text>Choose or randomly determine


1. I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong. 

2. I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me. 

3. The first thing I do in a new place is note the locations of everything valuable — or where such things could be hidden. 

4. I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy. 

5. I am incredibly slow to trust. Those who seem the fairest often have the most to hide. 

6. I don&#39;t pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds. 

7. The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can&#39;t do it. 

8. I blow up at the slightest insult.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Ideal</name><text>Choose or randomly determine


1. Honor: I don&#39;t steal from others in the trade. (Lawful). 

2. Freedom: Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Chaotic). 

3. Charity: I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Good). 

4. Greed: I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Evil). 

5. People: I&#39;m loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral). 

6. Redemption; There&#39;s a spark of good in everyone. (Good). </text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Bond</name><text>Choose or randomly determine


1. I&#39;m trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor. 

2. My ill - gotten gains go to support my family. 

3. Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back. 

4. I will become the greatest thief that ever lived. 

5. I&#39;m guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it. 

6. Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made.  That will never happen again.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Flaw</name><text>Choose or randomly determine


1. When I see something valuable, I can&#39;t think about anything but how to steal it. 

2. When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money. 

3. If there&#39;s a plan, I&#39;ll forget it. If I don&#39;t forget it, I&#39;ll ignore it. 

4. I have a "tell" that reveals when I&#39;m lying. 

5. I turn tail and run when things look bad. 

6. An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I&#39;m okay with that. </text><expanded>0</expanded></feat></background><class><name>Bard</name><hd>2</hd><wealth>5d4x10</wealth><slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><proficiency>1</proficiency><proficiency>5</proficiency><proficiency>105</proficiency><proficiency>109</proficiency><proficiency>112</proficiency><numClassSkills>3</numClassSkills><armor>light armor</armor><weapons>simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</weapons><tools>three musical instruments of your choice</tools><feat><name>Bardic Inspiration</name><text>You can inspire others through stirring words or music. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d6.
    Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Bardic Inspiration die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.
    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.
    Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 53</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the bard spell list.

Cantrips:
    You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn additional bard cantrips of your choice at higher levels, learning a 3rd cantrip at 4th level and a 4th at 10th level.

Spell Slots:
    The Bard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
    For example, if you know the 1st-level spell cure wounds and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast cure wounds using either slot.

Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:
    You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list.
    You learn an additional bard spell of your choice at each level except 12th, 16th, 19th, and 20th. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
    Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Spellcasting Ability:
    Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
    Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
    Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier

Ritual Casting:
    You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.

Spellcasting Focus:
    You can use a musical instrument (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 52</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><autolevel><slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Bardic Inspiration</name><text>You can inspire others through stirring words or music. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d6.
    Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Bardic Inspiration die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.
    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.
    Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 53</text></feat><feat><name>Magical Inspiration</name><text>1st-level bard feature (enhances Bardic Inspiration)
If a creature has a Bardic Inspiration die from you and casts a spell, the creature can roll that die and add the number rolled to one damage or healing roll of the spell. The Bardic Inspiration die is then lost.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Multiclass Bard</name><text>To multiclass as a Bard, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Charisma 13

You gain the following proficiencies:
• light armor, one skill of your choice, one musical instrument of your choice

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spell Versatility</name><text>1st-level bard feature (enhances Spellcasting)
Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the bard spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.

Rule Tip: Cantrips Are Spells:
   Cantrips are 0-level spells, which don&#39;t use spell slots. When a feature applies to spells, that feature applies to cantrips, unless the feature specifies that the spells must be of 1st level or higher or must expend a spell slot.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the bard spell list.

Cantrips:
    You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn additional bard cantrips of your choice at higher levels, learning a 3rd cantrip at 4th level and a 4th at 10th level.

Spell Slots:
    The Bard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
    For example, if you know the 1st-level spell cure wounds and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast cure wounds using either slot.

Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:
    You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list.
    You learn an additional bard spell of your choice at each level except 12th, 16th, 19th, and 20th. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
    Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Spellcasting Ability:
    Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
    Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
    Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier

Ritual Casting:
    You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.

Spellcasting Focus:
    You can use a musical instrument (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 52</text></feat><feat><name>Starting Bard</name><text>As a 1st-level Bard, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.

You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: light armor
• Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
• Tools: three musical instruments of your choice
• Skills: Choose any three

You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) a rapier, (b) a longsword, or (c) any simple weapon
• (a) a diplomat&#39;s pack or (b) an entertainer&#39;s pack
• (a) a lute or (b) any other musical instrument
• Leather armor and a dagger

Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 51</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Jack of All Trades</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn&#39;t already include your proficiency bonus.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text><special>3</special></feat><feat><name>Song of Rest</name><text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can use soothing music or oration to help revitalize your wounded allies during a short rest. If you or any friendly creatures who can hear your performance regain hit points at the end of the short rest by spending one or more Hit Dice, each of those creatures regains an extra 1d6 hit points.
    The extra hit points increase when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d8 at 9th level, to 1d10 at 13th level, and to 1d12 at 17th level.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Bard College</name><text>At 3rd level, you delve into the advanced techniques of a bard college of your choice: the College of Lore or the College of Valor, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th and 14th level.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Creation (UA)</name><text>Bards believe the multiverse was given existence through word and sound, esoteric harmonies that continue to resound through existence: the Song of Creation. The bards of this college draw on this ancient power through performances of dance, music, or song to bring into being what they need most.
Members of this college might have developed their powers during experiences on other worlds or planes of existence. Those who have seen the commonalities of multiple realities might have learned how to tap into truths most mortals glimpse only for a moment. Alternatively, the bard might find themselves out of step with their own home plane, reality, or time, their connections to elsewhere allowing them to manipulate the space around them. Regardless of where a bard draws their powers from, other performers might be drawn to them, either to learn their secrets or to put an end to their dangerous manipulation of the Song of Creation.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2020 Subclasses Pt2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Eloquence (UA)</name><text>Adherents of the College of Eloquence master the art of oratory. Persuasion is regarded as a high art, and a well-reasoned, well-spoken argument often proves more powerful than objective truth. These bards wield a blend of logic and theatrical wordplay, winning over skeptics and detractors with logical arguments, and plucking at heartstrings to appeal to the emotions of entire audiences.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Bard And Paladin</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Glamour</name><text>The College of Glamour is the home of bards who mastered their craft in the vibrant realm of the Feywild or under the tutelage of someone who dwelled there. Tutored by satyrs, eladrin, and other fey, these bards learn to use their magic to delight and captivate others. 
    The bards of this college are regarded with a mixture of awe and fear. Their performances are the stuff of legend. The bards of this college are so eloquent that a speech or song that one of them performs can cause captors to release the bard unharmed and can lull a furious dragon into complacency. The same magic that allows them to quell beasts can also bend minds. Villainous bards of this college can leech off a community for weeks, abusing their magic to turn their hosts into thralls. Heroic bards of this college instead use this power to gladden the downtrodden and undermine oppressors.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 14</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Lore</name><text>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales. Whether singing folk ballads in taverns or elaborate compositions in royal courts, these bards use their gifts to hold audiences spellbound. When the applause dies down, the audience members might find themselves questioning everything they held to be true, from their faith in the priesthood of the local temple to their loyalty to the king.
    The loyalty of these bards lies in the pursuit of beauty and truth, not in fealty to a monarch or following the tenets of a deity. A noble who keeps such a bard as a herald or advisor knows that the bard would rather be honest than politic.
    The college&#39;s members gather in libraries and sometimes in actual colleges, complete with classrooms and dormitories, to share their lore with one another. They also meet at festivals or affairs of state, where they can expose corruption, unravel lies, and poke fun at self-important figures of authority.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Swords</name><text>Bards of the College of Swords are called blades, and they entertain through daring feats of weapon prowess. Blades perform stunts such as sword swallowing, knife throwing and juggling, and mock combats. But though they use their weapons to entertain, they are also highly trained and skilled warriors in their own right.
    Their talent with weapons inspires many blades to lead double lives. One blade might use a circus troupe as cover for nefarious deeds such as assassination, robbery, and blackmail. Other blades strike at the wicked, bringing justice to bear against the cruel and powerful. Most troupes are happy to accept a blade&#39;s talent for the excitement it adds to a performance, but few entertainers fully trust a blade in their ranks.
    Blades who abandon lives as entertainers have often run into trouble that makes maintaining their secret activities impossible. A blade caught stealing or engaging in vigilante justice is too great a liability for most troupes. With their weapon skills and magic, these blades either take up work as enforcers for thieves&#39; guilds or strike out on their own as adventurers.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Valor</name><text>Bards of the College of Valor are daring skalds whose tales keep alive the memory of the great heroes of the past, and thereby inspire a new generation of heroes. These bards gather in mead halls or around great bonfires to sing the deeds of the mighty, both past and present. They travel the land to witness great events first hand and to ensure that the memory of those events doesn&#39;t pass from the world. With their songs, they inspire others to reach the same heights of accomplishment as the heroes of old.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bard College: College of Whispers</name><text>Most folk are happy to welcome a bard into their midst. Bards of the College of Whispers use this to their advantage. They appear to be like any other bard, sharing news, singing songs, and telling tales to the audiences they gather. In truth, the College of Whispers teaches its students that they are wolves among sheep. These bards use their knowledge and magic to uncover secrets and turn them against others through extortion and threats. 
    Many other bards hate the College of Whispers, viewing it as a parasite that uses the bards&#39; reputation to acquire wealth and power. For this reason, members of this college rarely reveal their true nature. They typically claim to follow some other college, or they keep their actual calling secret in order to infiltrate and exploit royal courts and other settings of power.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 16</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blade Flourish (College of Swords)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn to perform impressive displays of martial prowess and speed.
    Whenever you take the Attack action on your turn, your walking speed increases by 10 feet until the end of the turn, and if a weapon attack that you make as part of this action hits a creature, you can use one of the following Blade Flourish options of your choice. You can use only one Blade Flourish option per turn.

Defensive Flourish: You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die. You also add the number rolled to your AC until the start of your next turn.. 

Slashing Flourish: You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit and to any other creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die.

Mobile Flourish: You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die. You can also push the target up to 5 feet away from you, plus a number of feet equal to the number you roll on that die. You can then immediately use your reaction to move up to your walking speed to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target.

Frightened:
• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.

• The creature can&#39;t willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (College of Lore)</name><text>When you join the College of Lore at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with three skills of your choice.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (College of Swords)</name><text>When you join the College of Swords at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor and the scimitar.
    If you&#39;re proficient with a simple or martial melee weapon, you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (College of Valor)</name><text>When you join the College of Valor at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and martial weapons.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Combat Inspiration (College of Valor)</name><text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to inspire others in battle. A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can roll that die and add the number rolled to a weapon damage roll it just made. Alternatively, when an attack roll is made against the creature, it can use its reaction to roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to its AC against that attack, after seeing the roll but before knowing whether it hits or misses.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Cutting Words (College of Lore)</name><text>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to use your wit to distract, confuse, and otherwise sap the confidence and competence of others. When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a damage roll, you can use your reaction to expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and subtracting the number rolled from the creature&#39;s roll. You can choose to use this feature after the creature makes its roll, but before the DM determines whether the attack roll or ability check succeeds or fails, or before the creature deals its damage. The creature is immune if it can&#39;t hear you or if it&#39;s immune to being charmed.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Enthralling Performance (College of Glamour)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can charge your performance with seductive, fey magic. 
    If you perform for at least 1 minute, you can attempt to inspire wonder in your audience by singing, reciting a poem, or dancing. At the end of the performance, choose a number of humanoids within 60 feet of you who watched and listened to all of it, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be charmed by you. While charmed in this way, the target idolizes you, it speaks glowingly of you to anyone who talks to it, and it hinders anyone who opposes you, although it avoids violence unless it was already inclined to fight on your behalf. This effect ends on a target after 1 hour, if it takes any damage, if you attack it, or if it witnesses you attacking or damaging any of its allies. 
    If a target succeeds on its save against this effect, the target has no hint that you tried to charm it. 
    Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.

Charmed:
• A charmed creature can&#39;t attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.

• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 14</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Expertise</name><text>At 3rd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
    At 10th level, you can choose another two skill proficiencies to gain this benefit.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style (College of Swords)</name><text>At 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can&#39;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if something in the game lets you choose again.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Dueling (College of Swords)</name><text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional><special>2</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting (College of Swords)</name><text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Mantle of Inspiration (College of Glamour)</name><text>When you join the College of Glamour at 3rd level, you gain the ability to weave a song of fey magic that imbues your allies with vigor and speed. 
    As a bonus action, you can expend a use of Bardic Inspiration to grant yourself a wondrous appearance. When you do so, choose a number of allies you can see and who can see you within 60 feet of you, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each of them gains 5 temporary hit points. When a creature gains these temporary hit points, it can immediately use its reaction to move up to its speed, without provoking opportunity attacks.
    The number of temporary hit points increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 8 at 5th level, 11 at 10th level, and 14 at 15th level.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 14</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Note of Potential (College of Creation (UA))</name><text>3rd-level College of Creation feature
   You can manipulate the Song of Creation to summon a floating musical note of possibility: Whenever you give a creature a Bardic Inspiration die, you can create a Note of Potential. The note orbits within 5 feet of the creature. The note is a Tiny object that is intangible and invulnerable, and it lasts until the Bardic Inspiration die is lost. A creature with a note can use it in the following ways.

Note of Destruction
   Immediately after the creature rolls the Bardic Inspiration die to add it to an attack roll, the creature can expend the note to create a burst of sound. Each other creature within 5 feet of it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or take thunder damage equal to the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die.

Note of Protection
   Immediately after the creature rolls the Bardic Inspiration die and adds it to a saving throw, the creature can expend the note to gain temporary hit points equal to the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die + your Charisma modifier, provided the creature doesn&#39;t already have temporary hit points.

Note of Inspiration
   When the creature rolls the Bardic Inspiration die to add it to an ability check, the creature can expend the note to roll the Bardic Inspiration die again and choose which roll to use.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2020 Subclasses Pt2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Psychic Blades (College of Whispers)</name><text>When you join the College of Whispers at 3rd level, you gain the ability to magically make your weapon attacks toxic to a creature&#39;s mind. 
    When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to deal an additional 2d6 psychic damage to that target. You can do so only once per round on your turn. 
    The psychic damage increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 3d6 at 5th level, 5d6 at 10th level, and 8d6 at 15th level.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 16</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Soothing Words (College of Eloquence (UA))</name><text>3rd-level College of Eloquence feature
   You can now cast calm emotions without expending a spell slot. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you finish a long rest.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Bard And Paladin</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Universal Speech (College of Eloquence (UA))</name><text>3rd-level College of Eloquence feature
   You have gained the ability to speak and reason with any creature. As a bonus action, you can expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration. When you do so, roll your Bardic Inspiration die, and choose a number of creatures within 60 feet of you that you can see equal to the roll. For 10 minutes, the chosen creatures can magically understand you, regardless of the language you speak, and you have advantage on Charisma checks made to influence them. This feature works even on a creature that doesn&#39;t speak any languages.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Bard And Paladin</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Words of Terror (College of Whispers)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn to infuse innocent-seeming words with an insidious magic that can inspire terror.
    If you speak to a humanoid alone for at least 1 minute, you can attempt to seed paranoia in its mind. At the end of the conversation, the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be frightened of you or another creature of your choice. The target is frightened in this way for one hour, until it is attacked or damaged, or until it witnesses its allies being attacked or damaged.
    If the target succeeds on its save, the target has no hint that you tried to frighten it.
    Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a short rest or long rest.

Frightened:
• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.

• The creature can&#39;t willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 16</text><optional>1</optional></feat><tracker><label>Enthralling Performance</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker><tracker><label>Words of Terror</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#39;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
    If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Proficiency Versatility</name><text>4th-level feature (enhances Ability Score Improvement)
When you gain the Ability Score Improvement feature from your class, you can also replace one of your skill proficiencies with a skill proficiency offered by your class at 1st level (the proficiency you replace needn&#39;t be from the class).
This change represents one of your skills atrophying as you focus on a different skill.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Font of Inspiration</name><text>Beginning when you reach 5th level, you regain all of your expended uses of Bardic Inspiration when you finish a short or long rest.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Additional Magical Secrets (College of Lore)</name><text>At 6th level, you learn two spells of your choice from any class. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, or a cantrip. The chosen spells count as bard spells for you but don&#39;t count against the number of bard spells you know.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Animating Performance (College of Creation (UA))</name><text>   6th-level College of Creation feature
   Your mastery over the Song of Creation allows you to magically bring items to life. As an action, you can target a Large or smaller nonmagical item you can see within 30 feet of you and animate it. The animate item uses the Dancing Item stat block and is under your control for 1 hour or until it is reduced to 0 hit points.
   In combat, the item shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block or the Dash, Disengage, Help, Hide, or Search action.
   When you use your Bardic Inspiration feature, you can command which action your animated item takes as part of the same bonus action.
   In combat, the item shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yoOnce you animate an item with this feature, you can&#39;t do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 3rd level or higher to use this feature. You can have only one item animated by this feature at a time; if you use this action and already have a dancing item from this feature, the first one immediately becomes inanimate.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2020 Subclasses Pt2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Countercharm</name><text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to use musical notes or words of power to disrupt mind-influencing effects. As an action, you can start a performance that lasts until the end of your next turn. During that time, you and any friendly creatures within 30 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed. A creature must be able to hear you to gain this benefit. The performance ends early if you are incapacitated or silenced or if you voluntarily end it (no action required).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Extra Attack (College of Swords)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Extra Attack (College of Valor)</name><text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Mantle of Majesty (College of Glamour)</name><text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to cloak yourself in a fey magic that makes others want to serve you. As a bonus action, you cast command, without expending a spell slot, and you take on an appearance of unearthly beauty for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During this time, you can cast command as a bonus action on each of your turns, without expending a spell slot.
    Any creature charmed by you automatically fails its saving throw against the command you cast with this feature.
    Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a long rest.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 14</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Mantle of Whispers (College of Whispers)</name><text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to adopt a humanoid&#39;s persona. When a humanoid dies within 30 feet of you, you can magically capture its shadow using your reaction. You retain this shadow until you use it or you finish a long rest.
    You can use the shadow as an action. When you do so, it vanishes, magically transforming into a disguise that appears on you. You now look like the dead person, but healthy and alive. This disguise lasts for 1 hour or until you end it as a bonus action.
    While you&#39;re in the disguise, you gain access to all information that the humanoid would freely share with a casual aquaitance. Such information includes general details on its background and personal life, but doesn&#39;t include secrets. The information is enough that you can pass yourself off as the person by drawing on its memories.
    Another creature can see through this disguise but succeeding on a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by your Charisma (Deception) check, You gain a +5 bonus to your check.
    Once you capture a shadow with this feature, you can&#39;t capture another one with it until you finish a short or long rest.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 16</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Undeniable Logic (College of Eloquence (UA))</name><text>6th-level College of Eloquence feature
   You can spin words laced with magic into a knot of reasoning that can be encouraging or impossible to follow.
   As a bonus action, you can expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration. When you do so, choose a creature you can see within 60 of you that can hear you, then roll your Bardic Inspiration die and choose one of the following:
• The creature takes psychic damage equal to the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die, and the creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC or have disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.
• The creature regains hit points equal to the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die, and the creature has advantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Bard And Paladin</text><optional>1</optional></feat><tracker><label>Mantle of Majesty</label><type>1</type><resetType>2</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker><tracker><label>Mantle of Whispers</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>3,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#39;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
    If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Proficiency Versatility</name><text>8th-level feature (enhances Ability Score Improvement)
When you gain the Ability Score Improvement feature from your class, you can also replace one of your skill proficiencies with a skill proficiency offered by your class at 1st level (the proficiency you replace needn&#39;t be from the class).
This change represents one of your skills atrophying as you focus on a different skill.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><slots>3,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Magical Secrets</name><text>By 10th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.
    The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.
    You learn two additional spells from any class at 14th level and again at 18th level.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#39;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
    If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Proficiency Versatility</name><text>12th-level feature (enhances Ability Score Improvement)
When you gain the Ability Score Improvement feature from your class, you can also replace one of your skill proficiencies with a skill proficiency offered by your class at 1st level (the proficiency you replace needn&#39;t be from the class).
This change represents one of your skills atrophying as you focus on a different skill.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Battle Magic  (College of Valor)</name><text>At 14th level, you have mastered the art of weaving spellcasting and weapon use into a single harmonious act. When you use your action to cast a bard spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Infectious Inspiration (College of Eloquence (UA))</name><text>14th-level College of Eloquence feature
   When a creature adds one of your Bardic Inspiration dice to its ability check, attack roll, or saving throw and the roll fails, the creature can keep the Bardic Inspiration die.
   In addition, when a creature adds one of your Bardic Inspiration dice to its ability check, attack roll, or saving throw and the roll succeeds, you can use your reaction to encourage a different creature (other than yourself) that can hear you within 60 feet of you, giving it a Bardic Inspiration die without expending any of your Bardic Inspiration uses. You can use this reaction a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Bard And Paladin</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master&#39;s Flourish (College of Swords)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, whenever you use a Blade Flourish option, you can roll a d6 and use it instead of expending a Bardic Inspiration die.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 15</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Peerless Skill (College of Lore)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, when you make an ability check, you can expend one use of Bardic Inspiration. Roll a Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to your ability check. You can choose to do so after you roll the die for the ability check, but before the DM tells you whether you succeed or fail.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 55</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Performance of Creation (College of Creation (UA))</name><text>   14th-level College of Creation feature
   Your performance can manipulate the magic of creation, briefly transforming the world around you. As an action, you can create one nonmagical item of your choice in an unoccupied space within 10 feet of you. The item must appear on a surface or in a liquid that can support it. The gp value of the item can&#39;t be more than 20 times your bard level and must be Large or smaller. Tiny glimmering, intangible notes float around it, and a creature can faintly hear music when touching it. For examples of items you can create, see the Armor, Weapons, Adventuring Gear, Tools, and Mounts and Vehicles tables in chapter 5, “Equipment,” of the Player&#39;s Handbook.
   The created item disappears at the end of your next turn, unless you use your action to maintain it. Each time you use your action in this way, the item&#39;s duration is extended to the end of your next turn, up to a maximum of 1 minute. If you maintain the item for the full minute, it continues to exist for a number of hours equal to your bard level.
   Once you create an item with this feature, you can&#39;t do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 5th level or higher to use this feature. You can have only one item created by this feature at a time; if you use this action and already have an item from this feature, the first one immediately vanishes.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2020 Subclasses Pt2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Shadow Lore (College of Whispers)</name><text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to weave dark magic into your words and tap into a creature&#39;s deepest fears. 
    As an action, you magically whisper a phrase that only one creature of your choice within 30 feet of you can hear. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. It automatically succeeds if it doesn&#39;t share a language with you or if it can&#39;t hear you. On a successful saving throw, your whisper sounds like unintelligible mumbling and has no effect. 
    If the target fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for the next 8 hours or until you or your allies attack it, damage it, or force it to make a saving throw. It interprets the whispers as a description of its most mortifying secret. You gain no knowledge of this secret, but the target is convinced you know it. 
    The charmed creature obeys your commands for fear that you will reveal its secret. It won&#39;t risk its life for you or fight for you, unless it was already inclined to do so. It grants you favors and gifts it would offer to a close friend. 
    When the effect ends, the creature has no understanding of why it held you in such fear.
    Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a long rest.

Charmed:
• A charmed creature can&#39;t attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.

• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 16</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Unbreakable Majesty (College of Glamour)</name><text>At 14th level, your appearance permanently gains an otherworldly aspect that makes you look more lovely and fierce.
    In addition, as a bonus action, you can assume a magically majestic presence for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated. For the duration, whenever any creature tries to attack you for the first time on a turn, the attacker must make a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it can&#39;t attack you on this turn, and it must choose a new target for its attack or the attack is wasted. On a successful save, it can attack you on this turn but it has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against your spells on your next turn.
    Once you assume this majestic presence, you can&#39;t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 14</text><optional>1</optional></feat><tracker><label>Unbreakable Majesty</label><type>1</type><resetType>2</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker><tracker><label>Shadow Lore</label><type>1</type><resetType>2</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#39;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
    If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Proficiency Versatility</name><text>16th-level feature (enhances Ability Score Improvement)
When you gain the Ability Score Improvement feature from your class, you can also replace one of your skill proficiencies with a skill proficiency offered by your class at 1st level (the proficiency you replace needn&#39;t be from the class).
This change represents one of your skills atrophying as you focus on a different skill.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#39;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
    If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat><feat><name>Proficiency Versatility</name><text>19th-level feature (enhances Ability Score Improvement)
When you gain the Ability Score Improvement feature from your class, you can also replace one of your skill proficiencies with a skill proficiency offered by your class at 1st level (the proficiency you replace needn&#39;t be from the class).
This change represents one of your skills atrophying as you focus on a different skill.

Source: Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Superior Inspiration</name><text>At 20th level, when you roll initiative and have no uses of Bardic Inspiration left, you regain one use.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 54</text></feat></autolevel><spellAbility>5</spellAbility><spell><name>Detect Magic</name><school>3</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration><text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.
     The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 231</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Paladin</sclass><sclass>Ranger</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer</sclass></spell><spell><name>Disguise Self</name><school>6</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 hour</duration><text>You make yourself, including your clothing, armor, weapons, and other belongings on your person, look different until the spell ends or until you use your action to dismiss it. You can seem 1 foot shorter or taller and can appear thin, fat, or in between. You can&#39;t change your body type, so you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs. Otherwise, the extent of the illusion is up to you. 
    The changes wrought by this spell fail to hold up to physical inspection. For example, if you use this spell to add a hat to your outfit, objects pass through the hat, and anyone who touches it would feel nothing or would feel your head and hair. If you use this spell to appear thinner than you are, the hand of some one who reaches out to touch you would bump into you while it was seemingly still in midair. 
    To discern that you are disguised, a creature can use its action to inspect your appearance and must succeed on an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 233</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer</sclass></spell><spell><name>Mage Hand</name><school>2</school><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 minute</duration><text>A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again. 
    You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it. 
    The hand can&#39;t attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 256</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer</sclass></spell><spell><name>Message</name><school>8</school><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a short piece of copper wire</materials><duration>1 round</duration><text>You point your finger toward a creature within range and whisper a message. The target (and only the target) hears the message and can reply in a whisper that only you can hear. 
    You can cast this spell through solid objects if you are familiar with the target and know it is beyond the barrier. Magical silence, 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood blocks the spell. The spell doesn&#39;t have to follow a straight line and can travel freely around corners or through openings.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 259</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer</sclass></spell><spell><name>Prestidigitation</name><school>8</school><time>1 action</time><range>10 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Up to 1 hour</duration><text>This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice. You create one of the following magical effects within range: 
    • You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor. 
    • You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor. 
    • You instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire. 
    • You instantaneously clean or soil an object no larger than 1 cubic foot. 
    • You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving material for 1 hour. 
    • You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object or a surface for 1 hour. 
    • You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn. 
    If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 267</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer</sclass></spell><spell><name>Speak with Animals</name><school>3</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>10 minutes</duration><text>You gain the ability to comprehend and verbally communicate with beasts for the duration. The knowledge and awareness of many beasts is limited by their intelligence, but at minimum, beasts can give you information about nearby locations and monsters, including whatever they can perceive or have perceived within the past day. You might be able to persuade a beast to perform a small favor for you, at the DM&#39;s discretion.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 277</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Ranger</sclass></spell><spell><name>Tasha&#39;s Hideous Laughter</name><school>4</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>tiny tarts and a feather that waved in the air</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range perceives everything as hilariously funny and falls into fits of laugher if this spell affects it. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw of fall prone, becoming incapacitated and unable to stand up for the duration. A creature with an Intelligence score of 4 or less isn&#39;t affected.
    At the end of each of its turns, and each time it takes damage, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. The target has advantage on the saving throw if it&#39;s triggered by damage. On a success, the spell ends.

Incapacitated:
• An incapacitated creature can&#39;t take actions or reactions.

Prone:
• A prone creature&#39;s only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.

• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.

• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 280</text><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Warlock (Great Old One)</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell></class><container><name>Dungeoneer’s Pack</name><text>Includes a backpack, a crowbar, a hammer, 10 pitons, 10 torches, a tinderbox, 10 days of rations, and a waterskin. The pack also has 50 feet of hempen rope strapped to the side of it.</text><value>12.0</value><item><name>Backpack</name><value>2.0</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Hammer</name><value>2.0</value><weight>3.0</weight></item><item><name>Piton</name><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.05</value><weight>0.25</weight></item><item><name>Torch</name><text>A torch burns for 1 hour, providing bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. If you make a melee attack with a burning torch and hit, it deals 1 fire damage.</text><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.01</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Tinderbox</name><text>This small container holds flint, fire steel, and tinder (usually dry cloth soaked in light oil) used to kindle a fire. Using it to light a torch—or anything else with abundant, exposed fuel—takes an action. Lighting any other fire takes 1 minute.</text><value>0.5</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Rations (1 day)</name><text>Rations consist of dry foods suitable for extended travel, including jerky, dried fruit, hardtack, and nuts.</text><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.5</value><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Waterskin</name><value>0.2</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Hempen rope (50 feet)</name><text>Rope, whether made of hemp or silk, has 2 hit points and can be burst with a DC 17 Strength check.</text><value>1.0</value><weight>10.0</weight></item></container>
<item><name>Hunter&#39;s Coat</name><text>
      You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.
      The coat has 3 charges. When you hit a creature with an attack and that creature doesn&#39;t have all its hit points, you can expend 1 charge to deal an extra 1d10 necrotic damage to the target. The coat regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.
      The breastplate and shoulder protectors of this armor are made of leather that has been stiffened by being boiled in oil. The rest of the armor is made of softer and more flexible materials.
      Source: Explorer&#39;s Guide to Wildemount p. 267
    </text><type>1</type><slot>5</slot><value>10.0</value><weight>10.0</weight><ac>11</ac></item><item><name>Dagger</name><text>Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><slot>2</slot><value>2.0</value><weight>1.0</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Rapier</name><text>Proficiency: martial, rapier
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><value>25.0</value><weight>2.0</weight><damage1H>1d8</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>1026</weaponProperty><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Barrel</name><text>A barrel can hold 40 gallons of liquid or 4 cubic feet of solids.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 153</text><value>2.0</value><weight>70.0</weight></item><item><name>Amulet</name><text>A holy symbol is a representation of a god or pantheon 
    A cleric or paladin can use a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus, using it in place of any material components which do not list a cost. To use the symbol in this way, the caster must hold it in hand, wear it visibly, or bear it on a shield.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 151</text><value>5.0</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Gold (gp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>74</quantity><value>1.0</value><weight>0.02</weight></item><slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><money>74.0</money></character>
</pc>