<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger</name>
    <hd>10</hd>
    <proficiency>Strength, Dexterity,Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
    <armor>light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
    <weapons>simple weapons, martial weapons</weapons>
    <tools>none</tools>
    <numSkills>3</numSkills>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature>
        <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
        <text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
        <text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
        <text>Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
        <text>Tools: none</text>
        <text>Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Starting Equipment</name>
        <text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
        <text />
        <text>- (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor</text>
        <text>- (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons</text>
        <text>- (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
        <text>- A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</text>
        <text />
        <text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Favored Enemy</name>
        <text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.</text>
        <text>    Choose a type of favored enemy: aberrations, beasts, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, giants, monstrosities, oozes, plants, or undead. Alternatively, you can select two races of humanoid (such as gnolls and orcs) as favored enemies.</text>
        <text>    You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</text>
        <text>    When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice that is spoken by your favored enemies, if they speak one at all.</text>
        <text>    You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language, at 6th and 14th level. As you gain levels, your choices should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Natural Explorer</name>
        <text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you're proficient in.</text>
        <text>    While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits:</text>
        <text />
        <text>- Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.</text>
        <text>- Your group can't become lost except by magical means.</text>
        <text>- Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</text>
        <text>- If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
        <text>- When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</text>
        <text>- While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
        <text />
        <text>    You choose additional favored terrain types at 6th and 10th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deft Explorer (UA)</name>
        <text>You are an unsurpassed explorer and survivor. Choose one of the following benefits, and then choose another one at 6th and 10th level.</text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Canny
          Choose one skill: Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You gain proficiency in the chosen skill if you don't already have it, and you can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using that skill.
          In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write two languages of your choice.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Roving
          Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Tireless
          As an action, you can give yourself a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier. You can use this special action a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest. In addition, whenever you finish a short rest, your exhaustion level, if any, is decreased by 1.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Favored Foe (UA)</name>
        <text>
          You can call on your bond with nature to mark a creature as your favored enemy for a time: you know the hunter's mark spell, and Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it. You can use it a certain number of times without expending a spell slot and without requiring concentration—a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
          When you gain the Spellcasting feature at 2nd level, hunter's mark doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.
        </text>
        <text />
      </feature>
      <slots>0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Martial Versatility (UA)</name>
        <text>Whenever you gain a level in a class that has the Fighting Style feature, you can replace a fighting style you know with another style available to your class. This change represents a shift of focus in your martial training and practice, causing you to lose the benefits of one style and gain the benefits of another style. </text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Spellcasting</name>
        <text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Spell Slots</text>
        <text>The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
        <text>    For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher</text>
        <text>You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.</text>
        <text>    You learn an additional ranger spell of your choice at each odd numbered level thereafter. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
        <text>    Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
        <text>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
        <text>    Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
        <text>    Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Spell Versatility (UA)</name>
        <text>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the ranger spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Spellcasting Focus (UA)</name>
        <text>You can use a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus for your ranger spells. See chapter 5, “Equipment,” of the Player's Handbook for a list of things that count as druidic focuses.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Fighting Style</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Mariner, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
        <text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
        <text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
        <text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
        <text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Druidic Warrior (UA)</name>
        <text>
          You learn two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. They count as ranger spells for you, and Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for them. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the druid spell list.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Blind Fighting (UA)</name>
        <text>Being unable to see a creature doesn't impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it, provided the creature isn't hidden from you.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Interception (UA)</name>
        <text>When a creature you can see hits a target that is within 5 feet of you with an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + your proficiency bonus (to a minimum of 0 damage). You must be wielding a shield or a simple or martial weapon to use this reaction.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Thrown Weapon Fighting (UA)</name>
        <text>
          You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon.
          In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to the damage roll.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Unarmed Fighting (UA)</name>
        <text>
          Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier. If you strike with two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8.
          When you successfully start a grapple, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to the grappled creature. Until the grapple ends, you can also deal this damage to the creature whenever you hit it with a melee attack.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger Archetype</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate: Beast Master, Deep Stalker, or Hunter. Your choice grants features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter</name>
        <text>Emulating the Hunter archetype means accepting your place as a bulwark between civilization and the terrors of the wilderness. As you walk the Hunter's path, you learn specialized techniques for fighting the threats you face, from rampaging ogres and hordes of orcs to towering giants and terrifying dragons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Beast Master</name>
        <text>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world. United in focus, beast and ranger work as one to fight the monstrous foes that threaten civilization and the wilderness alike. Emulating the Beast Master archetype means committing yourself to this ideal, working in partnership with an animal as its companion and friend.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Hunter's Prey</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Colossus Slayer, Giant Killer, or Horde Breaker.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter's Prey: Colossus Slayer</name>
        <text>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it's below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter's Prey: Giant Killer</name>
        <text>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter's Prey: Horde Breaker</name>
        <text>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Beast Master: Ranger's Companion</name>
        <text>You gain a beast companion that accompanies you on your adventures and is trained to fight alongside you. Choose a beast that is no larger than Medium and that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower. Add your proficiency bonus to the beast's AC, attack rolls, and damage rolls, as well as to any saving throws and skills it is proficient in. Its hit point maximum equals its normal maximum or four times your ranger level, whichever is higher.</text>
        <text>    The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn't take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.</text>
        <text>    If you are incapacitated or absent, your beast companion acts on its own, focusing on protecting you and itself. It never requires your command to use its reaction, such as when making an opportunity attack.</text>
        <text>    Like any creature, the beast can spend hit dice during a short rest.</text>
        <text>    While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
        <text>    If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn't hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Primeval Awareness</name>
        <text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can use your action and expend one ranger spell slot to focus your awareness on the region around you. For 1 minute per level of the spell slot you expend, you can sense whether the following types of creatures are present within 1 mile of you (or within up to 6 miles if you are in your favored terrain): aberrations, celestials, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. This feature doesn't reveal the creatures' location or number.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Primal Awareness (UA)</name>
        <text>
          You can focus your awareness through the interconnections of nature: you learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class if you don't already know them, as shown in the Primal Awareness Spells table. These spells don't count against the number of ranger spells you know.
          Primal Awareness Spells
          Ranger
          Level Spell
          3rd   detect magic, speak with animals
          5th   beast sense, locate animals or plants
          9th   speak with plants
          13th  locate creature
          17th  commune with nature
          You can cast each of these spells once without expending a spell slot. Once you cast a spell in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
        <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,2,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Additional Favored Terrains</name>
        <text>You gain an additional favored terrain.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Additional Favored Enemy</name>
        <text>You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language. Your choice should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deft Explorer (UA)</name>
        <text>You are an unsurpassed explorer and survivor. Choose one of the following benefits, and then choose another one at 6th and 10th level.</text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Canny
          Choose one skill: Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You gain proficiency in the chosen skill if you don't already have it, and you can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using that skill.
          In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write two languages of your choice.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Roving
          Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Tireless
          As an action, you can give yourself a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier. You can use this special action a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest. In addition, whenever you finish a short rest, your exhaustion level, if any, is decreased by 1.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,2,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Defensive Tactics</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Escape the Horde, Multiattack Defense, or Steel Will.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Defensive Tactics: Escape the Horde</name>
        <text>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Defensive Tactics: Multiattack Defense</name>
        <text>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Defensive Tactics: Steel Will</name>
        <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Beast Master: Exceptional Training</name>
        <text>On any of your turns when your beast companion doesn't attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action on its turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
        <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Land's Stride</name>
        <text>Starting at 8th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</text>
        <text>    In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>0,4,3,2,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Hide in Plain Sight</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, you can spend 1 minute creating camouflage for yourself. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create your camouflage.</text>
        <text>    Once you are camouflaged in this way, you can try to hide by pressing yourself up against a solid surface, such as a tree or wall, that is at least as tall and wide as you are. You gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions. Once you move or take an action or a reaction, you must camouflage yourself again to gain this benefit.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fade Away (UA)</name>
        <text>
          You can use a bonus action to magically become invisible, along with any equipment you are wearing or carrying, until the start of your next turn.
          Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Additional Favored Terrains</name>
        <text>You gain an additional favored terrain.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deft Explorer (UA)</name>
        <text>You are an unsurpassed explorer and survivor. Choose one of the following benefits, and then choose another one at 6th and 10th level.</text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Canny
          Choose one skill: Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You gain proficiency in the chosen skill if you don't already have it, and you can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using that skill.
          In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write two languages of your choice.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Roving
          Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.
        </text>
        <text />
        <text>
          Tireless
          As an action, you can give yourself a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier. You can use this special action a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest. In addition, whenever you finish a short rest, your exhaustion level, if any, is decreased by 1.
        </text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,2,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Multiattack</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Volley or Whirlwind Attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Multiattack: Volley</name>
        <text>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon's range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Multiattack: Whirlwind Attack</name>
        <text>You can use your action to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Beast Master: Bestial Fury</name>
        <text>Your beast companion can make two attacks or use Multiattack (if available) when you command it to use the Attack action.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
        <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>0,4,3,3,1,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Vanish</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can't be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Additional Favored Enemy</name>
        <text>You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language. Your choice should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,1,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Superior Hunter's Defense</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Evasion, Stand Against the Tide, or Uncanny Dodge.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Superior Hunter's Defense: Evasion</name>
        <text>You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Superior Hunter's Defense: Stand Against the Tide</name>
        <text>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Hunter: Superior Hunter's Defense: Uncanny Dodge</name>
        <text>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Beast Master: Share Spells</name>
        <text>Beginning at 15th level, when you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can also affect your beast companion with the spell if the beast is within 30 feet of you.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,2,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
        <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,2,0</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Feral Senses</name>
        <text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can't see. When you attack a creature you can't see, your inability to see it doesn't impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it. You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn't hidden from you and you aren't blinded or deafened.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
        <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Foe Slayer</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter of your enemies. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
      </feature>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <!--Xanathars Guide to Everything Gloom Stalker-->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker (XGE)</name>
        <text>Gloom Stalkers are at home in the darkest places: deep under the earth, in gloomy alleyways, in primeval forests, and wherever else the light dims.  Most folk enter such places with trepidation, but a Gloom Stalker ventures boldly into the darkness, seeking to ambush threats before they can reach the broader world.  Such rangers are often found in the Underdark, but they will go any place where evil lurks in the shadows.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Gloom Stalker magic</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Gloom Stalker Spells table.  The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know</text>
        <text />
        <text>3 - disguise self</text>
        <text>5 - rope trick</text>
        <text>9 - fear</text>
        <text>13 - greater invisibility</text>
        <text>17 - seeming</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Dread Ambusher (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you master the are of the ambush.  You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Wisdom modifier.</text>
        <text />
        <text>At the start of your first turn of each combat, your walking speed increases by 10 feet, which lasts until the end of that turn.  If you take the Attack action on that turn, you can make one additional weapon attack as part of that action.  If that attack hits, the target takes and extra 1d8 damage of the weapon's damage type.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Umbral Sight (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.  If you already have darkvision from your rece, its range increases by 30 feet.</text>
        <text />
        <text>You are also adept at evading creatures that rely on darkvision.  While in darkness, you are invisible to any creature that relies on darkvision to see you in that darkness.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Iron Mind (XGE)</name>
        <text>By 7th level, you have honed your ability to resist the mind-altering powers of your prey.  You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.  If you already have this proficiency you instead gain proficiency in Intelligence or Charisma saving throws (your choice).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Stalker's Flurry (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you learn to attack with such unexpected speed that you can turn a miss into another strike.  Once on each of your turns when you miss with a weapon attack, you can make another weapon attack as part of the same action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Gloom Stalker: Shadowy Dodge (XGE)</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, you can dodge in unforeseen ways, with wisps of supernatural shadow around you.  Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you and doesn't have advantage on the roll, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on it.  You must use the feature before you know the outcome of the attack roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!--Xanathars Guide to Everything Horizon Walker-->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker (XGE)</name>
        <text>Horizon Walkers guard the world against threats that originate from other planes or that seek to ravage the mortal realm with otherworldly magic.  They seek out planar portals and keep watch over them, venturing to the Inner Planes and the Outer Planes as needed to pursue their foes.  These rangers are also friends to any forces in the multiverse - especially benevolent dragons, fey, and elementals - that work to preserve life and the order of the planes.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Horizon Walker spells (XGE)</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Horizon Walker Spells table.  The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.</text>
        <text />
        <text>3 - protection from evil and good</text>
        <text>5 - misty step</text>
        <text>9 - haste</text>
        <text>13 - banishment</text>
        <text>17 - teleportation circle</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Detect Portal (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to magically sense the presence of a planar portal.  As an action, you detect the distance nad direction to the closest planar portal within 1 mile of you.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
        <text />
        <text>See the "Planar Travel" section in chapter 2 of the Dungeon Master's Guide for examples of planar portals.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Planar Warrior (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you learn to draw on the energy of the multiverse to augment your attacks.</text>
        <text />
        <text>As a bonus action, choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you.  The next time you hit that creature on this turn with a weapon attack, all damage dealt by the attack becomes force damage, and the creature takes an extra 1d8 force damage from the attack.  When you reach 11th level in this class, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Ethereal Step (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you learn to step through the Ethereal Plane.  As a bonus action, you can cast the etherealness spell with this feature, without expending a spell slot, but the spell ends at the end of the current turn.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Once you use this feature you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Distant Strike (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 11th levek, you gain the ability to pass between the planes in the blink of an eye.  When you take the Attack action, you can teleport up to 10 feet before each attack to an unoccupied space you can see.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If you attack at least two different creatures with this action, you can make one additional attack with it against a third creature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker: Spectral Defense (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, your ability to move between planes enables you to slip through the planar boundaries to lessen the harm done to you during battle.  When you take damage from an attack, you can use your reaction to give yourself resistance to all of that attack's damage on this turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!--Xanathars Guide to Everything Monster Slayer-->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="Yes">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer (XGE)</name>
        <text>You have dedicated yourself to hunting down creatures of the night and wielders of grim magic.  A Monster Slayer seeks out vampires, dragons, evil fey, fiends and other magical threats.  Trained in supernatural techniques to over come such monsters, slayers are experts at unearthing and defeating mighty, mystical foes.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer: Monster Slayer magic (XGE)</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Monster Slayer spells table.  The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.</text>
        <text />
        <text>3 - protection from evil and good</text>
        <text>5 - zone of truth</text>
        <text>9 - magic circle</text>
        <text>13 - banishment</text>
        <text>17 - hold monster</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Hunter: Hunter's Sense (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to peer at a creature and magically descern how best to hurt it.  As an action, choose one creature you can see within 60 feet of you.  You immediately learn whether the creature has any damage immunities, resistances, or vulnerabilities and what they are.  If the creature is hidden from divination magic, you sense that it has no damage immunities, resistances, or vulnerabilities.</text>
        <text />
        <text>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer: Slayer's Prey (XGE)</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can focus your ire on one foe, increasing the harm you inflict on it.  As a bonus action, you designate one creature you can see within 60 feet of you as the target of this feature.  The first time each urn that you hit that target with a weapon attack, it takes an extra 1d6 damage from the weapon.</text>
        <text />
        <text>This benefit lasts until you finish a short or long rest.  It ends early if you designate a different creature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer: Supernatural Defense (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you gain extra resilience against your prey's assaults on your mind and body.  Whenvever the target of your Slayer's Prey forces you to make a saving throw and whenever you make an ability check to escape that target's grapple, add 1d6 to your roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer: Magic-User's Nemesis (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to thwart someone else's magic.  When you see a creature casting a spell or telporting within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction to try to magically foil it.  The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell DC, or its spell or teleport fails and is waisted.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Monster Slayer: Slayer's Counter (XGE)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you gain the ability to counterattack when your prey try to sabotage you.  If the target of your Slayer's Prey forces you to make a saving throw, you can use your reaction to make one weapon attack against the quarry.  You make this attack immediately before making the saving throw.  If your attack hits, your save automatically succeeds, in addition to the attack's normal effects.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>