<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Updated 2015/12/21 (Errata) -->
<compendium version="5">
	<item>
		<name>Tooth of the White Dragon</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text />
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text />
		<text>This legendary weapon is one of 9 blades that make up the Mouth of the Dragon.  The blade was forged in the icy breath of a long forgotten white dragon and as such the blade has a white, frosted look to it.  A giant milk quartz makes up the cross guard, the quartz is cut to resemble the outstretched limbs of a dragon, each claw clutching a blood red ruby.  The pommel is a circular disk with each side having the nine blades carved in it.  The hilt is wrapped in supple yeti hide.</text>
		<text />
		<text>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.  On a successful melee hit the blade, the target takes an extra 3d6 cold damage. In addition, while you hold the sword, you have vulnerability to fire damage.</text>
		<text />
		<text>In freezing temperatures, the blade sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</text>
		<text />
		<text>When you draw this weapon, you can extinguish all nonmagical flames within 30 feet of you. This property can be used once per short rest.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<text />
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
		<roll>3D6</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Flan's Longbow of Lightning</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,2H</property>
		<range>150/600</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Flan, a hero of a bygone god, had this bow crafted out of the heart of a yew tree for his quest to save the harbor master's daughter from the villainous goblin horde.  It was his lightning reflexes and essence that embed the yew shaft and provides the extra punch that this bow offers.</text>
		<text />
		<text>As part of an attack action, on the first successfully hit target, every creature in a 15 foot diameter radius from the target needs to make a Dexterity saving throw.  On a failed save, the creature takes 2d4 electrical damage, and no damage on a successful save.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon. A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text />
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<text />
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged damage +1</modifier>
		<roll>2d4</roll>
	</item>  
	<item>
		<name>Qwalth's Blade</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2></dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>L,F</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text />
		<text>This legendary shortsword is also known as a the Giant's hamstring, after the favored tactic of the renown fighter Qwalth.  In the age of Giants, Qwalth left the dwarven holds, along side his brethren, and joined battle to drive them back. This finely crafted mithril blade, golden crossguard and sapphire pommeled sword was almost as feared among the giants as Qwalth himself.  The legend of the pair during the wars was well warranted and often a turning point when they took the field.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This shortsword grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</text>
		<text />
		<text>When you hit a giant with it, the giant takes an extra 2d6 damage of the weapon's type and must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or fall prone. For the purpose of this weapon, "giant" refers to any creature with the giant type, including ettins and trolls.</text>
		<text />
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
		<roll>2D6</roll>
	</item>  
	<item>
		<name>Hecton the Bald' Striking Spear</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>V,T</property>
		<range>30/60</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text />
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands.</text>
		<text />		
		<text>This legendary weapon was created by the wizard Hecton the Bald.  In times long ago, his accuracy with his spells were legendary and only became more so after he crafted the spear.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The ash wood for the shaft has been petrified by the gaze of a Madusa.  The spear head is forged of damascus steel.  An ancient blue dragon's roar merged the two components of the spear into one unified object.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This spear grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. While you hold it, you gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls.</text>
		<text />
		<text>When thrown as part of an attack action, the spear will do an extra 3D6 of thunder damage on a successful hit.  This property can be used once per short rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">spell attacks +2</modifier>
		<roll>3D6</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Perthshire's Infernal Armor</name>
		<type>LA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>13</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Perthshire was a hero that often delved down into the depths of hell to battle Devils and Demons.  During his many raids he learned that if you properly harvested Devil skins and added specially prepared studs, it will make quite the suit of Studded Leather armor.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The bulk of the suit of armor is constructed from a pit fiend named Wrethzzoglich. His hide, tanned a dark red. The metal studs have taken on a black hue, to reflect the black nature of Wrethzzoglick's heart.</text>
		<text>You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Magical Resistance: the wearer of this armor has resistance to magic spells and magical effects</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Robe of the Morning Lord</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by a Cleric</text>
		<text />
		<text>This elegant garment is made from exquisite cloth of white, gray, and black. It is also adorned with silvery runes.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This magical garment is also known as the High Vestment of Lethander, legend has it that he was wearing it when he ascended to the outer planes.  After his ascension, his disciples donned the robes to continue his work on this plane.</text>
		<text />
		<text>You gain these benefits while wearing the robe:</text>
		<text>- If you aren't wearing armor, your base Armor Class is 15 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
		<text>- If you aren't wearing armor, the Robe also conveys the following spell like effects.</text>
		<text>The robe holds 15 charges for the following properties. It regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spells: While wearing the robe, you can use an action to expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability: Spiritual weapon (1 charges), daylight (at will), freedom of movement (3 charges), guardian of faith (3 charges), mass cure wounds (3d8 + 10 healing, 5 charges), firestorm (15 charges)</text>
		<text />
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +5</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Lendarth's Death Dance Bracers</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by a Fighter (Battle Master) or someone with the feat: Martial Adept</text>
		<text />
		<text>Lendarth was a legendary hero of a bygone era.  His death dance was a thing of beauty, often causing even his opponents to stare in wonder as death descended.  He made a heroic sacrifice in the Lich Wars opening battle.  He fell holding a bridge as the defeated army retreated.  This was his greatest dance, laying waste to the Lich lords skeleton troops.  Something in that fight was absorbed by the bracers he wore, for when they were given to his next of kin, his dance could be seen in her fighting style.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The bracers holds 5 charges.  It regains 1d4-1 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text>While wearing the bracers, as part of an attack action that uses a Battle Master Maneuver you can use one or more charges to increase the superiority die type by one category per charge expended. A d6 becomes a d8, d8 becomes a d10, d10 becomes a d12 and a d12 becomes a d20.</text>
		<text />
		<text>If the bracers remain at 0 charges for two consecutive days, it's enchantment is broken and it is now considered a mundane set of brackers.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mage Armor Spell</name>
		<type>LA</type>
        <magic>1</magic>
		<value>0gp</value>
		<weight>0</weight>
		<ac>13</ac>
		<stealth></stealth>
		<text>this is the mage armor spell translated into an item for use.</text>
		<text />
	</item>
</compendium>